Jose Mario Valencia

Full Stack Developer / Software Engineer

🛡 DOSQUEBRADAS, 661001, COLOMBIA 🕒 3112019985





La Mariana N. Dosquebradas, 661001 Colombia 3112019985

sejoma989@gmail.com



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Passionate and experienced Software Engineer, Scrum Fundamentals certified with 3 years of experience designing, developing, installing, testing, and maintaining software systems. Proficient in languages such as ReactJS, NodeJS, Python and PHP as web developer. For databases I use MongoDb for noSQL structures, mySQL and postgreSQL for relational schemas. My ability to effectively self-manage tasks, priorities and work, has allowed me to achieve success independent projects, also as a functional part of an **Engineering** development team.



LINKS

Linkedin GitHub Pages

SKILLS

JavaScript Node.js React Python **GIT**

REFERENCES References available upon request

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer at Lending Front Colombia, Pereira (remote)

March 2022 - June 2022

- Development, coding, testing and debugging of software artifacts of an US bank credit application developed in React 15 and python (2.7).
- Integration of third-party services embedded as APIs to the platform.
- Product requirements development cycle under SCRUM Met. (English)
- Teammate design and code review
- Integration and validation of new migrations to the Database
- Support for software QA and I/O performance optimization in a microservices architecture.

Full Stack React Developer at MICUENTO startup, Medellín

March 2021 - October 2021

- Analyzed, designed and developed a new platform with modern technologies alongside co-workers.
- Helped to provide industry-leading digital transformation solutions to a 100% face-to-face assessment model.
- Collaborated to create strategic initiatives to design, code, and test solutions in a microservices NodeJS backend
- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design frontend specifications using ReactJS and Typescript
- Worked to continually meet the expectation of stakeholders and users under Scrum Methodology hours paid.

Head of Systems Department at GMYS, Pereira

October 2019 - May 2020

- Head in charge of administrative functions of the systems department of a company dedicated to the monitoring of transport vehicles by satellite GPS.
- Support and development of a GPS monitoring with a national operation platform developed in bash and python (2.7)
- Development of new features, testing and maintenance of the monitoring platform under **Django** and python version 2.7
- Real-time failure review of the equipment and communication with the platform through the active "daemons" (bash) capturing monitoring data of +800 equipment by GSM



EDUCATION

IT and Communications specialist master's degree. Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira.

August 2021 - Present, est. end in 2022

Computer Systems Engineer.

Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira.

January 2012 – January 2019

Best ECAES-PRO 2018-1 score of all engineers at UTP.